Guide to the Dept. of Music Sound Recordings, 1956 - 1990
Duke University. University Archives
Dept. of Music Sound Recordings 1956 - 1990
Duke University. Dept. of Music
51 linear feet, Extent: 680 Items
Duke University. University Archives
In 1942, Duke University created the Department of Aesthetics, Art and Music. In 1960, the Department of Music formed as a separate department. Allan H. Bone, Duke professor from 1940 to 1983 and conductor of the Duke Symphony, was instrumental in the formation of the department. British composer Iain Hamilton was a faculty member for seventeen years. The Dept. of Music Sound Recordings collection contains audiotapes made between 1956 and 1990, primarily on 1/4 inch reel to reel tape, of the Duke Symphony Orchestra, the Duke Wind Symphony, the Duke Glee Club, the Ciompi Quartet, and the Duke Collegium Musicum, as well as other recordings related to the faculty and students of the Duke University Department of Music. There are also audiocassettes and a few videotapes. Faculty members represented include Jane Hawkins, Penelope Jensen, Randall Love, Robert Parkins, Fred Raimi, Claudia Warburg, and Ruth Friedburg. Other featured musicians are Milton Babbitt, Barbara Lister-Sink, Claudia Bloom, Boaz Sharon, and Bruce Berg. English.
uamusicsound
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Use of this collection requires the creation of listening copies from audiotapes or viewing copies from videotapes. However, University Archives does not have the equipment or the resources to make copies from reel-to-reel tape, U-Matic videocassettes, Betamax videocassettes, or open reel video. To arrange for the creation of use copies from these formats, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Provenance
The Dept. of Music Sound Recordings was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2005.
Historical Note
In 1942, Duke University created the Department of Aesthetics, Art and Music. In 1960, the Department of Music formed as a separate department. Allan H. Bone, Duke professor from 1940 to 1983 and conductor of the Duke Symphony, was instrumental in the formation of the department. British composer Iain Hamilton was a faculty member for seventeen years.
Collection Overview
The Dept. of Music Sound Recordings collection contains audiotapes made between 1956 and 1990, primarily on 1/4 inch reel to reel tape, of the Duke Symphony Orchestra, the Duke Wind Symphony, the Duke Glee Club, the Ciompi Quartet, and the Duke Collegium Musicum, as well as other recordings related to the faculty and students of the Duke University Department of Music. There are also audiocassettes and a few videotapes. Faculty members represented include Jane Hawkins, Penelope Jensen, Randall Love, Robert Parkins, Fred Raimi, Claudia Warburg, and Ruth Friedburg. Other featured musicians are Milton Babbitt, Barbara Lister-Sink, Claudia Bloom, Boaz Sharon, and Bruce Berg.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Babbitt, Milton, 1916-; Berg, Bruce, violinist; Bloom, Claudia; Sharon, Boaz; Bone, Allan H.; Ciompi Quartet; Duke Collegium Musicum; Duke University. Chapel Choir; Duke University. Dept. of Music; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University. Glee Club; Duke University. Symphony Orchestra; Duke University Wind Symphony; Friedberg, Ruth C., 1928-; Hamilton, Iain, 1922-; Hawkins, Jane; Jensen, Penelope; Lister-Sink, Barbara; Love, Randall; Parkins, Robert; Raimi, Fred; Sound recordings
Contents of Collection
- Accession UA2005-0060
  - Men's Glee Club Concerts, 1958-1969, 36 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 1)
  - Men's and Women's Glee Club, Chancel Singers, Chapel Choir, Madrigal Singers, 1958-1971, 37 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 2)
  - Chorale, 1970-1980, 29 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch, 9 sound cassettes. (Box 3)
  - Chorale, 1980-1987, 12 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 4)
  - Chorale, 1987, 4 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous recordings, 18 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch, 5 sound reels; 5-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Wind Symphony, NC Symphony, Duke Symphony Orchestra, 1975-1986, 26 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 6)
  - Guest Artist--Ernest White: Music for Organ and Strings, 1962, 4 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Flentrop Organ Dedication, 1976, 3 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Organ Symposium, 1976, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Flentrop Organ, Duke Chapel, 1978, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Collegium Musicum, 1974-1990, 24 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 7)
  - Robert Parkins, 1979-1980, 7 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Wood Symphony, 1990, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Ciompi Quartet, 1991, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Organ Recital, 1991, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Largo, Maryland, 1969, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DSO Bone and Kitchen, 1981, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 8)
  - Jonathan Bag Demo, 1990 and undated, 4 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DSO Bone and Kitchen, 1981, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Allan Bone, undated, 4 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Composers Forum, undated, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Organ Recital, 1990, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Tibor Szasz, 1990, 3 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Iain Hamilton, 1964, 8 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch, 2 sound reels; 5-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 9)
  - Student Recitals, Workshops, 1971-1972 and undated, 26 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Student Recitals, 1970-1972 and undated, 9 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch, 2 sound reels; 5-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 10)
  - Student Chamber Ensembles, 1989, 1 videocassette (Betamax).
  - Duke Collegium, 1986, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Music Department Retreat, undated, 4 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Biddle Building Dedication, 1974, 19 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DSO Jazz, 1975, 4 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 11)
  - Doc Dikeman, 1979, 3 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Ted Dikeman, undated, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - John Duke, 1963, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Guitar Slim performing for jazz history class, 1977, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Miscellaneous recordings, 6 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Big Band Bash, undated, 3 videocassettes (U-matic).
  - Untitled, undated, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 12)
  - Brother Yusef, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Encounters, 1982, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Lost Eden, 1982, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Encounters: Schoenberg, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Winterfest, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Mendelssohn-Schumann, 1982, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Encounters, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Student Composers, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Javanese Music and Dance, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Indonesian Puppet Performance, 1985, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Student Composers Concert, 1982-1983, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - The Last Straw, undated, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Michael Ching-Levees Opera, undated, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Five Evenings with Iain Hamilton, 1963, 20 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 13)
  - Third Music Educators Conference, 1964, 10 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Guest Artists: Ernest White, 1962, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Guest Artists: New York Brass Quintet, 1964, 3 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Chamber Concert Rehearsal, 1958, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Unlabeled, undated, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Milton Babbitt, undated, 3 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 14)
  - Iain Hamilton, Lukas Foss, Ronald Hodges, Hindemuth, 1965 and undated, 13 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony, 1958-1965 and undated, 15 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DUCB, 1960, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Faculty Recitals, 1962, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, Men's Glee Club, 1963-1974 and undated, 33 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 15)
  - Spring Dance Festival, 1970, 1 videoreel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch.
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, Boaz Sharon, Frederic Moses, 1963-1986 and undated, 35 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 16)
  - Hanks & Friedburg, undated, 6 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 17)
  - Collegium Musicum, 1978-1982, 8 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Kimbrough-Friedburg, 1975, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Wind Symphony, Duke Symphony, 1975-1988, 20 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, Student Concerts, 1965-1990, 35 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch, 1 sound reel; 5-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 18)
  - Duke Symphony, Little Symphony, Wind Symphony, Small Orchestra, 1956-1978, 16 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 19)
  - Student Concerto Concert, 1962, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Ciompi - Sharon, 1977, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Ciompi Quartet, 1975-1978, 4 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Claudia Erdberg, 1977, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Bloom Sisters, 1986, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke String Quartet, 1963, 4 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Barbara Lister-Sink, 1975, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Marcellus-Lail, 1976, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Claudia Bloom, 1982, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Faculty Chamber Music Program, 1962, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - John Hanks and Ruth Friedberg, 1974, 3 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 20)
  - Duke Madrigal Singers, undated, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DUCB, 1963, 1 sound reel; 5-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Concert Band, 1964, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - University of Michigan Symphony Band, 1965, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - University of Illinois Summer Orchestra, undated, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Illinois Summer Youth Music, 1960, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Symphony Pops, 1960, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - New York Philharmonic, undated, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Triangle Symphony, 1963, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - MDB Lectures, 1962, 3 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Duo Recital, 1964, 3 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Francis Perry, 1975, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Stephen Robinson, 1975, 1 sound reel; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Noye's Fludde, 1975, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Lister-Sink, 1976, 6 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Faculty Concert, 1965, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke String Quartet, 1963 and undated, 2 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Miscellaneous recordings, including Faculty Recitals, Songs of John Duke, Frances Redding, 1963-1977 and undated, 22 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch, 3 sound reels; 5-inch, 1/4 inch, 25 audiocassettes. (Box 21)
  - Faculty Recitals, 1979-1982, 42 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 22)
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, 1972-1978 and undated, 42 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 23)
  - Ciompi Quartet, 1970-1989, 36 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 24)
  - Ciompi Quartet, 1970-1989, 21 sound reels; 7-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 25)
  - Woody Shaw with Duke Jazz Ensemble, 1985, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 26)
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1982, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Evans Hanks Israeli Songs, 1981, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Joyce Peck, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Joyce Peck, 1981, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Collegium, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Joyce Peck, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Donna Coleman, 1988, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Collegium, undated, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 27)
  - Duke Musicum Collegium, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Student Recitals, 1988, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - George Taylor, 1984, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Randy Love, 1988, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Joyce Peck, 1984, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Fred Raimi, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - A. Ciompi, 1984, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Richard Luby, 1981, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Nelson Music Room, 1989, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Fred Raimi, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 28)
  - Claudia Bloom, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1981-1985, 6 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, 1980, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DSO Chamber, 1984, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DSO, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony, 1982, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Paul Jeffrey, 1989, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Jill Swisher with Duke Wind Symphony, 1984, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 29)
  - DSO, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Jan Herliniger, 1984, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Stravinsky and Duke Students, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Warburg-Battersby, undated, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Unlabeled, undated, 4 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Collegium, 1985, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Graduate Composer Concert, 1989, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1989, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Wind Symphony, 1990 and undated, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 30)
  - Collegium, 1981-1990, 4 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Claudia Bloom, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Claudia / Madeline Bloom, 1990, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Berg Recital, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Fred Raimi, 1985, 4 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Student Chamber Music, 1989, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Boaz Sharon, 1981, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - F. Raimi / J. Hawkins, 1982, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Loren Withers, 1982, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 31)
  - Randy Love, 1983-1985, 4 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Jensen, Moses, Hawkins, 1984, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Claudia Bloom, 1986, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Rebecca Troxler, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Hanks and Friedberg, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Performance Practice Workshop, 1990, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - B. Berg and R. Love, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Bruce Berg / Jane Hawkins, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Robert Parkins, 1986, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Robert Parkins, 1981-1985, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 32)
  - Peter Marshall, 1981-1984, 3 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - David Arcus, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Composers Concert, 1989, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Donna Coleman, 1988, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, 1981-1985, 4 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Jaffe Encounters, 1987, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Ciompi Quartet, 1981-1986, 13 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 33)
  - Ciompi Quartet, 1985, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch. (Box 34)
  - Steven Bishop, undated, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Claudia Erdburg and Jane Hawkins, 1981, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - George Taylor, 1981, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Fletcher Residents, 1983-1984, 2 sound reels; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - DSO, 1985, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Wind Symphony, 1988, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Lost Eden, 1983, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Musicum Collegium, 1989, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
  - Collegium Vocale, 1988, 1 sound reel; 10-inch, 1/4 inch.
Separated Material
Robert Hill, 1986:
1 sound reel; 12-inch, 1/4 inch.
Stored in the University Archives audio collection, Box D4.
Related Material
Allan H. Bone Papers, 1944-1989
Duke University Archives